<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><updated>2018-06-13T07:27:43-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Layer 5</title><subtitle>Characterizing and contrasting service meshes and related technologies.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Enterprise Path to Service Mesh</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/06/08/the-enterprise-path-to-servcie-mesh/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Enterprise Path to Service Mesh"/><published>2018-06-08T14:15:05-07:00</published><updated>2018-06-08T14:15:05-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/06/08/the-enterprise-path-to-servcie-mesh</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/06/08/the-enterprise-path-to-servcie-mesh/">&lt;h4&gt; Book: &lt;i&gt;The Enterprise Path to Service Mesh Architectures&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;By Lee Calcote&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As a technology leader, you have heard of service mesh architectures in context of microservices. This book will help answer common questions on service mesh architectures, through the lens of a large enterprise. A service mesh approach offers a lot of potential for creating robust and scalable applications, but also introduces new challenges. The book covers how to evaluate your organization’s readiness, the factors to consider when deciding upon which applications should be built from the ground up or converted with a new service mesh architecture, and offers a path of how you can get there.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The three most important things readers will learn from this book:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-left:25px&quot;&gt; &lt;li&gt; What is a service mesh and why do I need one? &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li style=&quot;margin-left:15px&quot;&gt; What are the different service meshes and how do they contrast?&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li style=&quot;margin-left:15px&quot;&gt; Where services meshes layer in with other technologies.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;When and why should I adopt a service mesh?&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li style=&quot;margin-left:15px&quot;&gt;What are popular deployment models and why?&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; What are practical steps to adopt a service mesh in my enterprise?&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; How do I fit a service mesh into my existing infrastructure?&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Publish date: July/August 2018&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Book: The Enterprise Path to Service Mesh Architectures By Lee Calcote</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/rhino.gif"/></entry><entry><title type="html">Istio: Up and Running</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/06/07/using-istio-workshop/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Istio: Up and Running"/><published>2018-06-07T14:15:05-07:00</published><updated>2018-06-07T14:15:05-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/06/07/using-istio-workshop</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/06/07/using-istio-workshop/">&lt;h4&gt; Book: &lt;i&gt;Istio: Up and Running&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;By Lee Calcote, Matt Baldwin&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Istio is a service mesh announced in 2017 and supported by Google, IBM, and Lyft. It is open-source, incorporates Envoy Proxy, a component developed and battle hardened at Lyft, and is one of the fastest growing solutions for connecting, managing, and securing microservices.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Over time, microservices become opaque as they become larger. This makes troubleshooting and management increasingly difficult and complex. Service meshes, like Istio, introduce a way for operators and developers to easily manage their microservices. Among a multitude of use cases, Istio allows users to manage and control traffic and API calls between services, introduce resiliency and robustness when the network itself becomes unstable, provide observability of the dependencies between services, policy enforcement, mTLS and service identity, and more.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The hope is that readers will:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;li style=&quot;margin-left:15px&quot;&gt; Gain a broad understanding of the service mesh Istio. It’s origins, current state, and future. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li style=&quot;margin-left:15px&quot;&gt; Be able to deploy, manage, and use Istio. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li style=&quot;margin-left:15px&quot;&gt; Be familiar with the components of Istio -- what they do, how to use them, common patterns and production scenarios.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li style=&quot;margin-left:15px&quot;&gt; Develop policies and manage them.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li style=&quot;margin-left:15px&quot;&gt; Secure their microservice.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li style=&quot;margin-left:15px&quot;&gt; A broad understanding of the Istio ecosystem.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li style=&quot;margin-left:15px&quot;&gt; How to engage with the community.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Publish date: January 2019&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Book: Istio: Up and Running By Lee Calcote, Matt Baldwin</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/primates.jpg"/></entry></feed>